{"questions":[{
    "question":"What was the Palestinian currency during the British Mandate ?",
    "choices":["Palestinian Shekel",
    "Palestinian Dinar",
    "Jeneh",
    "Jordanian Dinar"],
    "answer":"Jeneh"
    },{
    "question":"What is the population of Palestine ?",
    "choices":["5 million",
    "10 million",
    "15 million",
    "20 million"],
    "answer":"5 million"
    },{
    "question":"Which ancient Palestinian city is known for its association with Prophet Abraham and the Cave of the Patriarchs ?",
    "choices":["Bait Lahm (Bethlehem)",
    "Al-Khalil (Hebron)",
    "Nablus",
    "Samira (Samaria)"],
    "answer":"Al-Khalil (Hebron)"
    },{
    "question":"What does the olive branch represent for Palestinians ?",
    "choices":["Strength",
    "Peace",
    "Freedom",
    "Unity"],
    "answer":"Peace"
    },{
    "question":"What is the literacy rate in Palestine ?",
    "choices":["80.5%",
    "85.2%",
    "90.7%",
    "97.8%"],
    "answer":"97.8%"
    },{
    "question":"What animal appears on the Palestinian coat of arms ?",
    "choices":["Peacock",
    "Lion",
    "Eagle",
    "Wolf"],
    "answer":"Eagle"
    },{
    "question":"What is the predominant agricultural product of Palestine ?",
    "choices":["Wheat",
    "Rice",
    "Olives",
    "Cotton"],
    "answer":"Olives"
    },{
    "question":"When was the apartheid wall built in the West Bank ?",
    "choices":["2002",
    "2005",
    "1948",
    "1967"],
    "answer":"2002"
    },{
    "question":"Who is the “Bride of Yaffa” ?",
    "choices":["Dalal Al - Mughrabi",
    "Laila Khaled",
    "Shadia Abu Gazaleh",
    "Fatima Bernawi"],
    "answer":"Dalal Al - Mughrabi"
    },{
    "question":"Palestinian Prisoners Day is on which date ?",
    "choices":["April 17",
    "April 27",
    "November 15",
    "November 25"],
    "answer":"April 17"
    },{
    "question":"What makes up the majority of the economy in Al-Khalil (Hebron) ?",
    "choices":["Trading",
    "Farming grapes and producing dairy products",
    "Consideration",
    "Glass shops"],
    "answer":"Farming grapes and producing dairy products"
    },{
    "question":"Which ancient city in Palestine is traditionally considered one of the oldest continuously inhabited cities in the world ?",
    "choices":["Bait Lahm (Bethlehem)",
    "Ariha (Jericho)",
    "Nablus",
    "Al-Khalil (Hebron)"],
    "answer":"Ariha (Jericho)"
    },{
    "question":"What is the lowest place on earth that is located in Palestine ?",
    "choices":["Ariha (Jericho)",
    "The Dead Sea",
    "Al-Khalil (Hebron)",
    "Nablus"],
    "answer":"The Dead Sea"
    },{
    "question":"What is the highest top/mountain or hill in Palestine ?",
    "choices":["Mount Nabi Yunis",
    "Tall `Asur",
    "Jabal Nablus",
    "Mount Gerizim"],
    "answer":"Mount Nabi Yunis"
    },{
    "question":"How many Palestinian refugees are there today ?",
    "choices":["7 million",
    "5 million",
    "4 million",
    "10 million"],
    "answer":"7 million"
    },{
    "question":"What Palestinian dish is the city of Al-Khalil (Hebron) most known for ?",
    "choices":["Maqlupa",
    "Dawali",
    "Qidrah",
    "Knafeh"],
    "answer":"Qidrah"
    },{
    "question":"Which Palestinian village is known for its unique tradition of Maftoul making?",
    "choices":["Ein Kerem",
    "Battir",
    "Silwan",
    "Jifna"],
    "answer":"Jifna"
    },{
    "question":"Which town is famous for its high-quality olive oil and wine production ?",
    "choices":["Beit Sahour",
    "Beit Jala",
    "Deir Istiya",
    "Al-Jib"],
    "answer":"Beit Jala"
    },{
    "question":"Which village is known for its ancient churches, including the Church of Saint Barbara ?",
    "choices":["Aboud",
    "Silwan",
    "Nabi Samwil",
    "Biddu"],
    "answer":"Aboud"
    },{
    "question":"Which city is famous for its age old soap making industry, knafeh dessert, olive wood furniture, and was also called “Little Damascus” in the past ?",
    "choices":["Al-Khalil (Hebron)",
    "Nablus",
    "Ariha (Jericho)",
    "Tulkaram"],
    "answer":"Nablus"
    },{
    "question":"Which city is in the Northern-most governorate of Palestine, as well as an important symbol of Palestinian resistance ?",
    "choices":["Ramallah",
    "Jenin",
    "Ramleh",
    "Yaffa"],
    "answer":"Jenin"
    },{
    "question":"Who is the artist behind the famous Handala cartoon ?",
    "choices":["Naji al Ali",
    "Sliman Mansour",
    "Susan Abulhawa",
    "Raeda Saadeh"],
    "answer":"Naji al Ali"
    },{
    "question":"Which village is known for its stunning landscapes, ancient terraced agriculture, and significant archaeological sites including Roman ruins ?",
    "choices":["Al-Walaja",
    "Beit Sahour",
    "Ein Kerem",
    "Beit Jala"],
    "answer":"Al-Walaja"
    },{
    "question":"Which village in East Jerusalem is famous for the City of David archaeological site and its ancient water systems ?",
    "choices":["Silwan",
    "Nabi Samwil",
    "Beit Surik",
    "Battir"],
    "answer":"Silwan"
    },{
    "question":"Which village in the West Bank is known for its annual almond harvest festival and traditional cultural activities associated with the festival ?",
    "choices":["Battir",
    "Biddu",
    "Deir Istiya",
    "Artas"],
    "answer":"Biddu"
    },{
    "question":"Who is the Palestinian author known for his novel 'Men in the Sun,' which explores the struggles of Palestinian refugees?",
    "choices":["Mahmoud Darwish",
    "Ghassan Kanafani",
    "Emile Habibi",
    "Samira Azzam"],
    "answer":"Ghassan Kanafani"
    },{
    "question":"Who is the Palestinian author and scholar known for his work 'Palestinian Identity: The Construction of Modern National Consciousness' ?",
    "choices":["Edward Said",
    "Elias Khoury",
    "Rashid Khalidi",
    "Aziz Shihab"],
    "answer":"Rashid Khalidi"
    },{
    "question":"Which Palestinian author is known for his novel 'Mornings in Jenin,' which portrays the Palestinian experience through generations of a refugee family ?",
    "choices":["Susan Abulhawa",
    "Raja Shehadeh",
    "Ghassan Kanafani",
    "Susan Muaddi Darraj"],
    "answer":"Susan Abulhawa"
    },{
    "question":"Which Palestinian film, directed by Najwa Najjar, tells the story of a young Palestinian woman's experience in an Israeli prison ?",
    "choices":["3000 Nights",
    "Omar",
    "Wajib",
    "Divine Intervention"],
    "answer":"3000 Nights"
    },{
    "question":"Which ancient site in Palestine is known for its large, monolithic statues dating back to the 10th century BCE ?",
    "choices":["Megiddo",
    "Jerash",
    "Tell el-Ful",
    "Tell es-Sultan"],
    "answer":"Tell es-Sultan"
    },{
    "question":"Which ancient Palestinian city, located in the northern West Bank, is known for its archaeological remains, including a Roman theater and Hippodrome ?",
    "choices":["Ramallah",
    "Jerash",
    "Jericho",
    "Sebastia"],
    "answer":"Sebastia"
    },{
    "question":"Which city is famous for having some of the most reputed tatreez (embroidery) artisans and a characteristic white Thdatae with intricate red tatreez ?",
    "choices":["Tulkarm",
    "Gaza City",
    "Ramallah",
    "Nablus"],
    "answer":"Ramallah"
    },{
    "question":"In which year did Israel exchange all settlements in Gaza for others in the west bank ?",
    "choices":["2002",
    "2005",
    "1948",
    "1967"],
    "answer":"2005"
    },{
    "question":"what is the national tree of Palestine ?",
    "choices":["Orange tree",
    "Olive tree",
    "Fig tree",
    "Cedar tree"],
    "answer":"Olive tree"
    },{
    "question":"What does the colour green in the Palestinian flag represent ?",
    "choices":["Olives",
    "The Fatimid dynasty",
    "Fertile Arab lands",
    "B and C"],
    "answer":"B and C"
    },{
    "question":"When is the earliest recorded mention of Palestine ?",
    "choices":["5th century BC",
    "1948",
    "2nd century BC",
    "1967"],
    "answer":"5th century BC"
    },{
    "question":"What Palestinian city was a major port before the Nakba ?",
    "choices":["Gaza",
    "Haifa",
    "Yaffa",
    "Akka"],
    "answer":"Yaffa"
    },{
    "question":"Where areas did Palestine export to before The Nakba ?",
    "choices":["From Egypt and the eastern Mediterranean to the Levant",
    "To coastal areas surrounding the Arabian Sea",
    "the Americas",
    "Europe"],
    "answer":"From Egypt and the eastern Mediterranean to the Levant"
    },{
    "question":"What is the desert surrounding the Dead Sea called ?",
    "choices":["Empty Quarter",
    "Al-Naqab",
    "Eastern Desert",
    "Barr Al-Khalil"],
    "answer":"Barr Al-Khalil"
    },{
    "question":"Famous Palestinian author and poet Ghassan Kanafani was born in ?",
    "choices":["Akka (Acre)",
    "Jenin",
    "Al-Quds (Jerusalem)",
    "Al-Khalil (Hebron)"],
    "answer":"Akka (Acre)"
    },{
    "question":"What city is famous for its Zaatar and citrus fruit orchards?",
    "choices":["Tulkarm",
    "Al-Khalil (Hebron)",
    "Al-Quds (Jerusalem)",
    "Haifa"],
    "answer":"Tulkarm"
    }]
    }
   




    

